Guide to the American Women's Himalayan Expedition, Inc.: files, 1974-1984
Department of Special Collections
Beardsley, Irene A., collector. American Women's Himalayan Expedition, Inc.: files,
1974-1984
M1220
Beardsley, Irene A., collector.
3 linear ft. (2 record storage boxes)
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Irene Beardsley was a member of the successful expedition of 1978 to Annapurna; she maintained this collection of files. The collection includes research, correspondence, logistics, equipment, legal and financial files for the expedition. Also included is a signed copy of Arlene Blum's ANNAPURNA; A WOMAN'S PLACE, 1980.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Irene A. Beardsley, 2001.
Biography
Irene Beardsley was a member of the successful expedition of 1978 to Annapurna; she maintained this collection of files.
Scope and Content
Includes research, correspondence, logistics, equipment, legal and financial files for the expedition. Also included is a signed copy of Arlene Blum's ANNAPURNA; A WOMAN'S PLACE, 1980.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Ashton, Marie.; Beardsley, Irene A.; Blum, Arlene, 1945-; Chadwick-Onyszkiewicz, Alison.; Firey, Joan.; Komarkova, Vera.; Kramar, Piro.; Klobusicky-Mailaender, Liz.; Miller, Irene B.; Ortenburger, Irene B.; Rusmore, Margi.; Taylor, Dyanna.; Tews, Christy.; Watson, Vera.; Whitehouse, Annie.; aAmerican Women's Himalayan Expedition, Inc.; aAnnapurna Expedition, (1978); Mountaineering--Nepal--Annapurna.; Mountaineering expeditions.; Women mountaineers--United States.; Annapurna; a woman's place.
Collection Contents
- Correspondence with American Alpine Club and Nepal1973 Apr. 9 - 1977 Apr. 12 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Contains correspondence regarding application for permission to climb Annapurna in fall of 1978 by the AWHE. Also an earlier application for an international women's group to climb in the spring of 1975
  Blum, Arlene; Cheney, M. J.; de la Vega, Frank; Firey, Joan; Fischer, David J.; Henriot, James F.; Miller, Irene B.; Panday, Mohan B.; Porzak, Glenn E.; Watson, Vera; American Alpine Club; Ministry of Foreign Affairs - Nepal
- (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Contains information regarding American Alpine Club's first expedition to Nepal including
  Blum, Arlene; Firey, Joan
- Nepal Mountaineering Rules1976 Jan. 26 - 1978 June 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Contains the mountaineering rules of Nepal and a copy of the application for permission to climb Annapurna in fall of 1978 by the AWHE.
  Blum, Arlene; Cheney, M. J.; Ministry of Foreign Affairs - Nepal
- Dutch Expedition 19771978 Jan. 1 - 1978 Mar. 7 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Contains correspondence with members of Dutch expedition that climbed Annapurna in 1977 by the Dutch Rib, and copies of related articles.
  Verrijn-Stuart, A. A.; Wildervanck, Lucas W.; Royal Dutch Alpine Club
- Other Expeditions1976 Jan. 16 - 1977 Dec. 6 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Contains correspondence with members of other expeditions to Annapurna and other Nepalese peaks.
  Anglada, Jose Manuel; Carter, H. Adams; Day, M. W. Henry; Henriot, James F.; Miller, Irene; Ovchinnikov, A.; Poliakov, A.; Putnam, William L.; Read, Al; Van Meter, Steve; Watson, Vera; Wilson, Bob; American Bicentennial Everest Expedition; American Alpine Club; Expedicion Espanola al Annapurna; British Nepalese Army Annapurna Expedition 1970; American Annapurna III Expedition 1978
- Minutes of AWHE Meetings1976 Jan. 21 - 1978 Apr. 9 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Minutes of meetings of AWHE expedition members and supporters working on planning and fund raising.
- Fund Raising - Fact Sheets, Press Releases1977 - 1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Drafts of publicity for fund raising, copy of NY TImes article.
- Fund Raising - Tee Shirts1977 - 1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Flier for Sacramento event, various documents and tee shirt order forms.
  Formoso, Sandy
- Fund Raising - Treks1978 Feb. 13 - 1979 Feb. 15 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Cost estimates, advertising, correspondence related to the two treks organized for fund raising.
  Gallo, Penny Howe; Hanley, Mary Lynn; Miller, Irene B.; Group Travel Adventures
- Legal - Incorporation of AWHE1977 Aug. 22 - 1982 Mar. 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Legal documents of incorporation and unincorporation of AWHE, with related correspondence.
  Blum, Arlene; Gallo, Penny Howe; Blasgen, Sharon; Miller, Irene B.; Watson, Vera; Ware, Fletcher & Freidenrich
- Corporate Donations1977 Dec. 12 - 1979 May 24 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Correspondence related to corporate fundraising.
  Bacon, Glenn C.; Blasgen, Sharon; Miller, Irene B.; Moloney, Vincent G.; Vandenberg, Jeffrey J.; Watson, Vera; IBM; Johnson & Johnson; WM. Underwood Company
- Donations to AWHE - 11977 Aug. 6 - 1979 Jan. 27 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Many letters accompaning personal donations to AWHE before the expedition left in August 1978.
  Miller, Colin
- Donations to AWHE - 21978 Jan. 26 - 1979 Mar. 26 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Many letters accompaning personal tax-deductible donations to AWHE through the American Alpine Club, thanks to AAC sponsorship. Also periodic reports from the AAC of donations received.
  de la Vega, Frank; American Alpine Club
- Donations - Copies of Checks Deposited by AWHE1978 Mar. 23 - 1978 July 17 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Copies of checks from individuals sent to AWHE during 1978.
- Donations - Printout 1978 July 10 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Computer listing of all individuals donating money to AWHE up to July 10, 1978.
- Logistics1978 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Notes on logistics of Dutch 1977 expedition. Estimated logistics for AWHE. Account balance, Mar. 1, 1978.
  Prochazka, Ingeborg
- Food1977 Nov 11 - 1979 May 14 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Food planning and evaluation afterwards.
  Arnolt, Rick; Firey, Joan; Hart, John A.
- Medical1978 Feb. 7 - 1979 Oct. 19 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Correspondence concerning medical planning, purchase of oxygen bottles and masks from earlier expeditions.
  McGowan, Richard; Kramar, Piro; Verrijn-Stuart, A. A.; Watson, Vera
- Research1977 July 18 - 1979 Sept. 12 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Correspondence concerning possible high altitude research to be carried out by AWHE, including physiological studies by Barbara Drinkwater at UC Santa Barbara.
  Cheney, M. J.; Drinkwater, Barbara L.; Fisher, Sandra Lotz; Hultgren, Herbert N.; Kramar, Piro; Miller, Irene B.; Park, C. G.; Swan, Kenneth C.; Talbot, John H.; American Alpine Club; University of California, Santa Barbara; Stanford University
- Equipment Lists - Other Expeditions1977 - 1978 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Equipment lists from several other expeditions, including Everest the Hard Way, American Jannu Expedition 1978, and lists for Sirdar and High Altitude Porters from Himalayan Society.
  Clarke, Dave
- Equipment - Before1977 Nov. 28 - 1979 Nov. 6 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Correspondence regarding equipment; final equipment lists; info on radios, tents; list of corporations donating equipment; shipping info.
  Miller, Colin; Miller, Irene B.; Ortenburger, Leigh; Watson, Vera; Marmot Mountain Works, Ltd.; Pacific Westbound Conference
- Equipment - Members' Lists1978 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Specification from each member of needed equipment and sizes.
- Equipment 3 - in Nepal1978 July - 1978 Oct. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Lists of all goods taken to Nepal, to be consumed in Nepal and to be re-exported. Breakdown by package. Contents of boxes as repacked in 65 lb loads to be carried by porters. Boxes for the higher camps. List of corporations making equipment donations, and printout of addresses.
- Equipment 4 - Afterwards1978 July 18 - 1979 Sep. 17 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Correspondence with corporations regarding equipment used.
  Raymond K. Andresen; Nancy Fletcher; Robert E. Foster; Vera Komarkova; A. H. McNally; C. H. Moore; Lyn David Sabala; Uniroyal, Inc; Dunlop Japan, Ltd.; Kelly Advertising, Inc.; Bridgeport Metal Goods Mfg. Co.; Scott USA; Camp Trails
- Budget1978 - 1980 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Budget estimates for the climb, and proposed budget for 1980 - 1981.
- Invoices - Before1978 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Contains invoices for equipment, food, other miscellaneous services, and for reimbursement of expenses by expedition members, all before the expedition left the USA.
- Correspondence - M. J. Cheney, Sherpa Cooperative1977 Jan. 12 - 1979 Apr. 28 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Correspondence between AWHE and M. J. Cheney, the head of Sherpa Coop in Nepal, who became our representative with the Nepal government and our source of Sherpas.
  M. J. Cheney; Vera Watson; Sherpa Cooperative Trekking Ltd.
- Invoices - in Nepal1978 Jul. - 1978 Oct. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Sherpa Coop bills for the base camp reconnoitre, pay for Sherpas, pay for porters, and other miscellaneous receipts.
  M. J. Cheney; Sherpa Cooperative Trekking Ltd.
- Nepal Expenses - Summary1978 May 29 - 1978 Nov. 28 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Setting up of bank account in Nepal. Summary of expenses while in Nepal.
  Irene B. Miller; .
- Invoices After - 11978 Sep. - 1980 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Miscellaneous invoices for services after the expedition returned.
- Invoices After - 21978 Sep. - 1980 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Members' Expenses1978 Sep. - 1980 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Invoices from AWHE members for expenses both before and after the expedition.
  .
- AWHE - Taxes 11977 July 15 - 1979 June 26 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Articles of incorporation and corporate income tax returns and related correspondence.
  Penny Howe Gallo; Ware, Fletcher, and Freidenrich
- AWHE - Taxes 21979 July 19 - 1980 May 16 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- AWHE - Taxes 31980 May 23 - 1984 Jan. 31 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Penny Howe Gallo; Anne Hightower; Noreene Wilson; Ware, Fletcher, and Freidenrich
- AWHE - Taxes 41983 Apr. 14 - 1985 Apr. 1 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Corporate income tax returns and related correspondence.
  Noreene Wilson
- AWHE - Taxes 51985 Jan. 6 - 1987 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Correspondence related to dissolution of AWHE as a corporation.
  Timothy M. Ames; Arlene Blum; Noreene Wilson
- Checking Account Registers1977 July 5 - 1984 Jan. 31 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Checking account registers.
- Checking Account Statements1981 Feb. 27 - 1987 Aug. 31 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  Checking account statements.
  Crocker National Bank; Wells Fargo
- Cashfund Account1979 Oct. 26 - 1985 Nov. 29 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Registers and statements from cashfund account with Paine Webber.
  Paine Webber
- National Geographic1977 Oct. 5 - 1979 Jan. 19 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Correspondence concerning support from and article in National Geographic.
  Arlene Blum; Gilbert M. Grosvenor; Joseph R. Judge; Melinda Sanders; National Geographic
- Other Articles by Members1978 Dec. 15 - 1979 Nov. 29 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Three drafts of article written by Vera Komarkova for American Alpine Journal. Draft of article by Piro Kramar for "The Physician and Sports Medicine". Copy of article by Joan Firey in The Mountaineer. Exerpts from diaries of Vera Komarkova and Irene Miller.
  Arlene Blum; Barbara Drinkwater; Joan Firey; Vera Komarkova; Piro Kramar; Irene B. Miller; American Alpine Club
- Income - Photos1978 June 2 - 1981 Sept.17 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Correspondence concerning income from use of photos.
  Eva S. Auchincloss; Chris Dadarria; Colin Miller; Lorraine Rorke; John Schultz; Lynn Thompson; National Geographic; Funk and Wagnalls Inc.; Chicago Tribune; Women's Sports Foundation; The Great Pacific Iron Works; Contemporary Perspectives, Inc.
- Slide Shows - 11978 - 1979 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Correspondence concerning slide shows.
  Ed Bennett; Jim Burn; Robert W. Fortner; Ty Hisatomi; Raymond Lester; Irene Miller; Helen Rogers; Val Sherman; Mary Ann Simpson; Margy Sloan; Claire Stegmann; Susan Rebecca Wels; Cilla Whiteman; Gloria Williams; Betsy Wood; Barbara Zeldin
- Slide Shows - 21979 - 1982 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Marty Belknap; Marian Blair; Abby Boyd; Claudia Doerr; Donna Ericson; Donna Tepe Garton; Ed Gilmore; Muriel J. Gunn; Christine Halamka; Richard Hechtel; Joan Holland; Olive Horrell; Kristi Johnson; John P. Kennedy; Kitty Mason; Irene B. Miller; Rod Newcomb; Gertrude Pocha; mary Anne Simpson; June Burlingame Smith; Jack Stewart
- Film - Other Proposals1977 - 1978 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Correspondence concerning possible filmmakers.
  Marie Ashton; Robert Carmichael; Leila Dargahi; Steve Marts; Robert G. McBride; Sheila Page; Carol M. Rosebaum; Margaret A. Smilow; Dyanna Taylor; Richter McBride Productions Inc.
- AWHE Film - 11978 Aug. 6 - 1979 Mar. 4 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Film agreement, progress report, footage guide.
  Marie Ashton; Dyanna Taylor; ABC American Sportsman
- AWHE Film - 21979 Mar. 7 - 1982 Sept. 17 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Agreement between AWHE, Ashton, Taylor, and ABC Sports. Correspondence related to production and showing of film, and ownership and storage of film materials. Amendment to film agreement. Letter about movie script based on book.
  Diane Altwein; John R. Amatt; Marie Ashton; Freude Bartlett; Irene A. Beardsley; Arlene Blum; Leonard Franklin; Penny Howe Gallo; Marvin A. Gluck; Dyanna Taylor; Richard W. Poe; Ted Winterburn; ABC Sports, Inc.; ABC; Ware, Fletcher, and Freidenrich; Franklin, Weinrib, Rudell and Vassallo, P>C>; Annapurna - A Woman's Place
- AWHE Film - 31981 Sept. 21 - 1983 Oct. 8 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Contract with Serious Business Company for marketing film. Related correspondence. Information on several film festivals.
  Freude Bartlett; Terry L Byrnes; Paul A. Epstein; Anne Hightower; Diana Muirhead; Serious Business Company; Annapurna - A Woman's Place
- AWHE Film - 41981 Feb. 16 - 1984 Apr. 1 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Invoices for storage of film original materials by Bonded Services.
  Bonded Services; Annapurna - A Woman's Place
- AWHE Film - 51980 May 15 - 1981 Aug. 9 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Correspondence about accounting of film-related expenses. Dyanna Taylor's expenses. Letter about distribution agreement with Women Make Movies.
  Marie Ashton; Irene A. Beardsley; Terry Byrnes; Dyanna Taylor; Women Make Movies; Annapurna - A Woman's Place
- Smiley Correspondence1981 Mar. 19 - 1983 Dec. 29 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Letters from Guy Smiley to Irene Beardsley concerning a paper on the expedition for a course in women's history at SUNY-Binghampton, New York. Draft of summary of paper.
  Irene A. Beardsley; Guy. R. Smiley
- File Index1981 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Index of files of Irene Beardsley and Vera Watson, prepared by Guy Smiley, history student at SUNY-Binghamton NY. These file categories are no longer valid.
  Guy R. Smiley
- Hoff Correspondence1979 Mar. 8 - 1980 Dec. 8 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Correspondence concerning "Encounters in Excellence" speakers program for middle school students.
  Norman Baker; Christopher M. Ballister; Jens Bjerre; Gordon Cawelti; Helen R. Gerhardt; Joseph W. Hoff; James B. Irwin; Dewitt Jones; Richard C. Kern; Robert M. Lancto; Robert M. Malinka; Irene B. Miller; William R. Pogue; Louis Romano; Bob Roney; Russell L Schweickart; Robert R. Spillane; Thomas A. Sterling; John. H. Swaim; Scott D. Thomson; Conrad F. Toepfer, Jr.; Theodore J. Walker; Stanton A. Waterman
- Media Correspondence1979 Mar. 8 - 1980 Dec. 8 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Correspondence concerning interviews and public appearances for Irene Miller.
  Joseph R. Judge; Essie E. Lee; George Merlis; Colin Miller; Irene B. Miller; Susan Rebecca Wels; National Geographic; IBM; Think Magazine; Stanford Alumni Association; ABC Entertainment; Hunter College
- AWHE Newsletter Mailing Lists1979 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  Two sets of mailing labels of supporters of the expedition dated roughly January 1979.
- Mailing Lists1978 - 1979 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  Various lists of names and addresses of AWHE supporters.
- Office Memos - Colin Miller1978 Dec. 12 - 1979 Apr. 5 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  Handwritten memos of business conducted by Colin Miller immediately after the expedition.
  Colin Miller
- Vera Watson - Miscellaneous1977 July 2 - 1978 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  Miscellaneous correspondence to Vera Watson. Photo of Vera at pre-expedition party.
  Arlene Blum; Allison Clough; Gayle Costello; Irmgard Dobler; Terry Anderson Pearce; Vera Watson
- Climbing Directory1977 July 2 - 1978 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  Correspondence related to publication of a Women's Climbing Directory by AWHE and Woodswomaen
  Arlene Blum; Denise Miller; Kethy Phibbs; Woodswomen
- Summer Meets1978 Dec. 19 - 1982 May 25 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  Corespondence related to summer meets of AWHE supporters in 1979, 1980, 1981, 1982. Letter from Janusz Onyszkiewics (husband of Alison Chadwick) and information on British fund commemorating Alison.
  Arlene Blum; Alison Chadwick-Onyszkiewics; Colin Miller; Janusz Onyszkiewics; Merriby Sweet
- Donations to AWHE and VWACO 1978 Oct. 31 - 1980 May 27 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  Early donations through AWHE to the Vera Watson Alison Chadwick-Onyszkiewicz Memorial Fund, set up to support women climbers and later run through the American Alpine Club.
  M. J. Cheney; Frank de la Vega; Nancy K. Evans; Helen E. Howell; Piro Kramar; Jim Love; Colin Miller; Helen Rogers; Gloria E. Williams; Margaret Hughes Yound; VWACO Fund
- Grants Funded by AWHE1978 Dec. 28 - 1986 May 9 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  Applications directly to AWHE for grants for women's expeditions from spring of 1982 to 1986.
  Susan X. Billings; Lydia Bradey; Evelyn Lees; Krystyna Palmowska; Danuta Wach; Toby Weiss; Rick Wyatt; VWACO Fund
- VWACO Fund - Spring 19801980 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Applications and grants funded by VWACO for spring of 1980. Reports of expecitions.
  Stacey Marie Allison; Susan Coons; Diane Dailey; Elizabeth Doyle; Sue Giller; Sallie M. Greenwood; Nancy Goforth; Susan Havens; Nancy A. Holzwarth; Shari Kearney; Vera Komarkova; Debra Luraas; Heidi Ludi; Lindi McIlwhine; Karen Elena Laverne Rosene; Cyndy Simer; Lucy Smith; Saranne Taylor; Christy Tews; Rebecca Upham; Annie Whitehouse; VWACO Fund
- VWACO Fund - Spring 19811981 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  Applications and grants funded by VWACO for spring of 1981. Expedition reports.
  Stacy Allison; Kathy Anderson; Irene A. Beardsley; Susan Anne Giller; Sallie Greenwood; Vera Komarkova; Anne Macquarie; Kathy Phibbs; Colleen M. Sleavin; Toby Weiss; VWACO Fund
- VWACO Fund - Fall 19811981 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Applications and grants funded by VWACO for fall of 1981. Expedition reports.
  Stacy Allison; Irene Beardsley; Cherie Bremer-Kamp; Sue Giller; Jini Griffiths; Susan Havens; Tanya Lee Irwin; Shari Kearney; Heidi Ludi; Anne Macquarie; Lucy Smith; VWACO Fund
- VWACO Fund - Spring 19821982 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  Applications and grants funded by VWACO for spring of 1982. Expedition reports.
  Irene A. Beardsley; Catherine Freer; Melissa Jenkins; T. C. Price Zimmerman; Frank de la Vega; VWACO Fund
- VWACO Fund - Fall 1982 - French-American Women's Climbing Exchange1982 June 19 - 1984 May 21 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  Applications and grants funded by VWACO for the French-American Women's Climbing Exchange, in which six American climbers travelled to Paris and climbed with French hosts.
  Isabelle Agresti; Sandra Winslow Childs; Rhea Dodd; Susan Giller; Pat Haythorn; Alison Osius; Teri Kane Savelli; Toby Weiss; Rick Wyatt; VWACO Fund
- VWACO Fund - Spring 19831983 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  Applications and grants funded by VWACO for spring of 1983. Expedition reports.
  Arlene Blum; Christine de Colombel; Anna Czerwinska; Marxh Fraser; Michele A. Girts; Sue Giller; Pat Hudson; Dana Isherwood; Shari Kearny; Vera Komarkova; Evelyn Lees; Gerri Sue Lent; Anne Macquarie; Sarah C. Michael; Marty O"Keefe; Anna Okopinska; Alison Osius; Krystyna Palmowska; Carol Rubenstein; Virginia Seiser; Lucy Smith; Anne Tournay; Danuta Wach; Toby Weiss; Annie Whitehouse; VWACO Fund
- VWACO Fund - Fall 19831983 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  Applications and grants funded by VWACO for fall of 1983. Expedition reports.
  Donna M. Kalal; VWACO Fund
- VWACO Fund - Spring 19841984 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Applications and grants funded by VWACO for spring of 1984. Expedition reports.
  Carlos Buhler; Jo-Anne Christensen; Sallie Greenwoor; Gwen Hall-Hargis; Nancy Elizabeth Kerrebrock; Vera Komarkova; Alice M. Krueper; Maureen Mary O'Neill; Kathy Phibbs; Kate M. Reiss; Wendy E. Roberts; Emelie Scheult; Ruth Steinman; Dina Stervoba; Elizabeth White; Carolyn J. Wilson; Karen M. Wojcieson; Sharon Wood; VWACO Fund
- VWACO Fund - Fall 19841984 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  Applications and grants funded by VWACO for fall of 1984. Expedition reports.
  Doris L. Bowers; Catherine Freer; Priscilla McKenney; Julia Louise Wright; VWACO Fund
- VWACO Fund - 19851985 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  Applications and grants funded by VWACO for 1985. Expedition reports.
  Todd Bibler; Catherine Freer; Jonell Geller; Dana Isherwood; Renny Jackson; Maureen O'Neill; Kathy Phibbs; Sandy Stewart; VWACO Fund
- VWACO Fund - 19861986 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  Applications and grants funded by VWACO for 1986. Expedition reports.
  Elizabeth H. Archel; Stacy Marie Allison Austin; Julie Brugger; Paula Brutz; Julie-Anne Clyma; Kathleen Giel; Sue Giller; Dana Isherwood; Shari Kearney; Margaret Magennis; Alison Osius; Helen Padday; Anne Maria Palmer; Lucy Smith; Paula Turley; Annie Whitehouse; VWACO Fund
- VWACO Fund - 19871987 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  Applications and grants funded by VWACO for 1987. Expedition reports.
  Beverly J. Boynton; Catherine Freer; Kathleen Mary Giel; Sibylle C. Hechtel; Kathy Phibbs; Dana Isherwood; Roberta Hutchison; Evelyn C. Lees; Melly Ruelling; Miriam Lee Stone; VWACO Fund
- VWACO Fund - 19881988 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  Applications and grants funded by VWACO for 1988. Expedition reports.
  Arlene Blum; Kathy Giel; Sue Giller; Shari Kearney; Carol J. Snetsinger; Betsy White; Annie Whitehouse; VWACO Fund
- VWACO Fund - Contributions1979 Mar. - 1984 Sept. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  American Alpine Club statements listing contributions to the VWACO Fund from March 1979 to September 1984.
  American Alpine Club; VWACO Fund
- VWACO Fund - Committee Meetings and Correspondence1979 Mar. 28 - 1994 Mar. 14 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  Agreement between AWHE and the American Alpine Club to establish the Vera Watson/Alison Chadwick-Onyskiewicz fund for promoting women's mountaineering. Committee minutes, press releases, correspondence. Applications from 1988 on.
  Arlene Blum; Irene A. Beardsley; Katherine Giel; Sallie Greenwood; Dana Isherwood; Lou Reichardt; T. C. Price Zimmermann; American Alpine Club; VWACO Fund
- "Annapurna A Woman's Place," by Arlene Blum1980 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  Signed copy of Annapurna A Woman's Place by Arlene Blum, the story of the 1978 climb of Annapurna by the American Women's Himalayan Expedition.
  Arlene Blum
- Summit Magazine1978 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  Summit Magazine April-May 1978 Volume 24, Number 2, with article "American Women to Attempt Annapurna I, by Vera Watson and Irene Miller.
  Vera Watson; Irene B. Miller